their King, and he promised to come back and rule over them as soon as Dorothy
was safely on her way to Kansas end of Chapter 21 this is a librivox recording
all librivox recordings are in the public domain for more information or to
volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay Hall The Wonderful
Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum chapter 22 The Country of the Quadlings The four
travelers pass through the rest of the forest and safety, and when they came out
of its gloom saw before them a steep hill, covered from top to bottom with
great pieces of rock. “That will be a hard climb,” said the Scarecrow, “but we must get
over the hill, nevertheless.” So he led the way and the others followed. They had
nearly reached the first rock when they heard a rough voice cry out, “Keep back!”
“Who are you?” asked the Scarecrow. Then a head showed itself over the rock and the
same voice said, “This hill belongs to us, and we do not allow anyone to cross it.”
“But we must cross it,” said the Scarecrow we are going to the country of the Quadlings.”
“But you shall not!” replied the voice, and their step from behind the rock the
strangest man the travelers had ever seen. He was quite short and stout and
had a big head, which was flat at the top and supported by a thick neck full of
wrinkles. But he had no arms at all, and, seeing this, the Scarecrow did not fear
that so helpless a creature could prevent them from climbing the hill. So
he said I am sorry not to do as you wish,
but we must pass over your hill whether you like it or not,”
and he walked boldly forward. As quick as lightning the man’s head shot forward
and his neck stretched out until the top of his head, where it was flat, struck the
Scarecrow in the middle and sent him tumbling, over and over, down the hill.
Almost as quickly as it came the head went back to the body, and the man
laughed harshly as he said, “It isn’t as easy as you think!” A chorus of boisterous
laughter came from the other rocks, and Dorothy saw hundreds of armless hammer
heads upon the hillside, one behind every rock. The Lion became quite angry at the
laughter caused by the scarecrows mishap, and giving a loud roar that echoed like
thunder, he dashed up the hill. Again a head shot swiftly out, and the great Lion
went rolling down the hill as if he had been struck by a cannonball Dorothy ran
down and helped the Scarecrow to his feet, and the Lion came up to her, feeling
rather bruised and sore, and said, “It is useless to fight people with shooting
heads; no one can withstand them.” “What can we do, then?” she asked. “Call the Winged
Monkeys,” suggested the Tin Woodman.
“You still have the right to command them once more.” “Very well,” she answered, and
putting on the Golden Cap she uttered the magic words. The Monkeys were as
prompt as ever, and in a few moments the entire band stood before her. “What are
your commands?” inquired the King of the Monkeys, bowing low. “Carry us over the
hill to the country of the Quadlings,” answered the girl. “It shall be done,”
said the King, and at one the Winged Monkeys caught the four
travelers and Toto up in their arms and flew away with them. As they passed over
the hill the hammerheads yelled with vexation, and shot their heads high in
the air, but they could not reach the Winged Monkeys, which carried Dorothy and
her comrades safely over the hill and set them down in the beautiful country
of the Quadlings. “This is the last time you can summon us,” said the leader to
Dorothy; “so goodbye and good luck to you goodbye and thank you very much,” returned
the girl; and the Monkeys rose into the air and were out of sight in a twinkling.
The country of the Quadlings seemed rich and happy. There was field upon field of
ripening grain, with well paved roads running between, and pretty rippling
brooks with strong bridges across them.
The fences and houses and bridges were all painted bright red, just as they had
been painted yellow in the country of the Winkies and blue in the country of
the Munchkins. The Quadlings than themselves, who were short and fat and
looked chubby and good-natured, were dressed all in red, which showed bright
against the green grass and the yellow grain. The Monkeys had set them down near
a farmhouse, and the four travelers walked up to it and knocked at the door.
It was opened by the farmer’s wife, and when Dorothy asked for something to eat
the woman gave them all a good dinner, with three kinds of cake and four kinds
of cookies, and a bowl of milk for Toto.
“How far is it to the Castle of Glinda?” asked the child. “It is not a great way,”
answered the farmer’s wife. “Take the road to the South and you will soon reach it.”
Thanking the good woman, they started afresh and walked by the fields and
across the pretty bridges until they saw before them a very beautiful Castle.
Before the gates were three young girls, dressed in handsome red uniforms trimmed
with gold braid; and as Dorothy approached, one of them said to her: “Why
have you come to the South Country?” “To see the Good Witch who rules here,” she
answered. “Will you take me to her?” “Let me have your name, and I will ask Glinda if
she will receive you.” They told who they were, and the girl soldier went into the